Bijay Bohora

Full Stack Software Engineer

Full stack developer, been developing in React for 4+ years, including Typescript, JavaScript ES6+, Next.js, Redux, Node.js/express, RESTful APIs, MongoDB and more. Always looking to learn every day and develop great relations with clients and teams.

PROJECTS

Issue & Project Tracking Full Stack App

https://issue-tracker2.vercel.app/ https://github.com/Bijayb37/IssueTracker2

- Built Single Page Application with ReactJS, Redux, Reactrouter, React hooks, ES6,7,8 and Bootstrap
- Created Custom backend server built with NodeJS, ExpressJS, RESTful APIs, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM
- Built Authentication with bcrypt and jsonwebtoken
- Full CRUD operations for projects, issues, and comments
- Error management on front end for guiding users and custom errors on backend for guiding developers
- Responsive UI for desktop and mobile with bootstrap and normal CSS
- Figma used for design details and pixel perfect CSS
- Implemented integration and unit testing using RTL and Jest

Friends Chat App with NextJS & Typescript

https://firebase-chatrooms.vercel.app/ https://github.com/Bijayb37/Firebase-chatrooms

- Built using React, Typescript, NextJS, Firebase App
- Utilizes ES6,7,8 syntax with promises, async await, arrow functions
- Send and receive real-time messages using a cloud database
- Implemented Firebase auth (OAuth 2) for authentication and firebase Firestore for the database.
- Used Chakra-UI for frontend development and responsive styling

WORK EXPERIENCE

Disability Support Worker

Self Employed | March 2020 - Current

- Meeting, finding, and building relationships with clients
- Understanding a client's unique needs, preferences, and personality
- Effective communication and empathy required to support another person

McDonald's

Crew Trainer | March 2014 – March 2020

- Communicated roles for the team members, and taught new crew to deliver best possible service.
- Motivated staff every shift to do best possible work and not get caught up in the challenges.

Email:

bijay.work37@gmail.com

Phone: 0422369242 Location: Melbourne

GitHub: github.com/Bijayb37

Portfolio:

https://bijaywork.vercel.app/

SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript (ES6+), Typescript, HTML, CSS-in-JS, CSS, SASS/SCSS, Python, C++, Java, PHP, Bash/zsh

Libraries & Framework

React, Next.js, Node.js, Express, Chakra-Ul, Redux, React-Router, Material-Ul, Bootstrap, Figma

Tools & Platforms

Git, Firebase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Git, Webpack, mySQL, MariaDB, RESTful APIs

Testing

React Testing Library, Jest

Work & Personal

Agile software development, MVC, collaborative and communicative, easy to get along with

EDUCATION

Swinburne University of Technology

Bachelors Computer Science, Major in data science – 2021

Masters
Data Science- 2021 - current

Udemy

- The Modern React Bootcamp
- The Web Developer Bootcamp

LANGUAGES

English Nepalese